<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technology on Content</title><link>https://garthjacques.github.io/tags/technology/</link><description>Recent content in Technology on Content</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garthjacques.github.io/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How malicious AI swarms can threaten democracy</title><link>https://garthjacques.github.io/library/how-malicious-ai-swarms-can-threaten-democracy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garthjacques.github.io/library/how-malicious-ai-swarms-can-threaten-democracy/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-malicious-ai-swarms-can-threaten-democracy"&gt;How malicious AI swarms can threaten democracy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fusion of agentic AI and LLMs marks a new frontier in information warfare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advances in AI offer the prospect of manipulating beliefs and behaviors on a population-wide level [1]. Large language models (LLMs) and autonomous agents [2] now let influence campaigns reach unprecedented scale and precision. Generative tools can expand propaganda output without sacrificing credibility [3] and inexpensively create falsehoods that are rated as more human-like than those written by humans [4, 3]. Techniques meant to refine AI reasoning, such as chain-of-thought prompting, can just as effectively be used to generate more convincing falsehoods. Enabled by these capabilities, a disruptive threat is emerging: swarms of collaborative, malicious AI agents. Fusing LLM reasoning with multi-agent architectures [2], these systems are capable of coordinating autonomously, infiltrating communities, and fabricating consensus efficiently. By adaptively mimicking human social dynamics, they threaten democracy. Because the resulting harms stem from design, commercial incentives, and governance, we prioritize interventions at multiple leverage points, focusing on pragmatic mechanisms over voluntary compliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Software and Anarchy</title><link>https://garthjacques.github.io/library/software-and-anarchy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garthjacques.github.io/library/software-and-anarchy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Gnuxie Lulamoon and Hayley Patton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draft of April 17, 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is dedicated, in respect and admiration, to the spirit that lives on the computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="preface"&gt;Preface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book covers our interpretations of programming as it relates to social ecology, a philosophical theory that suggests many forms of dominion have the same causes and methods, and peer production, a self-organising mode of production, and how their application can support a radical programmer exceptionally well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>